<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Moxie Blog</title><link href="http://moxielogic.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://moxielogic.github.io/blog/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://moxielogic.github.io/blog/</id><updated>2014-12-18T05:00:00-05:00</updated><entry><title>Moxiebox and bitcoin</title><link href="http://moxielogic.github.io/blog/moxiebox-and-bitcoint.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-18T05:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>green</name></author><id>tag:moxielogic.github.io/blog,2014-12-18:moxiebox-and-bitcoint.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img alt="http://bitcoin.org" src="http://moxielogic.org/images/Bitcoin-logo.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more interesting developments around moxie is the adoption
of the &lt;a href="http://moxielogic.org/blog/pages/architecture.html"&gt;moxie
architecture&lt;/a&gt; by
the core bitcoin developers (&lt;a href="http://garzikrants.blogspot.ca/"&gt;Jeff
Garzik&lt;/a&gt;, in particular), for an
experimental project called
&lt;a href="http://github.com/jgarzik/moxiebox"&gt;&lt;code&gt;moxiebox&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote Jeff...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is to provide a secure, sandboxed execution mechanism that enables deterministic input, processing and output. Execution is separated out into distinct phases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare and load hash-sealed program executables, data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execute program as a black box, with no I/O capability. Runs until exit or CPU budget exhausted (or CPU exception).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gather processed data, if any.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single thread of execution pre-loads necessary data, then simulates a 32-bit little endian Moxie CPU, running the loaded code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't pretend to have deep understand bitcoin technology, but my
basic understanding is that moxiebox could be used to implement
automated smart contracts.  For instance, signed moxiebox executables
controlling a certain number of bitcoins could be distributed in the
&lt;a href="block%20chain"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitcoin#The_block_chain&lt;/a&gt;.  These programs would decide what to do with the bitcoins
based on program execution against certain input.  People could
independently verify the results of this program because it's all
designed to be completely deterministic and reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a moxie tooling perspective, I added a moxiebox target to the GNU
toolchain to simplify its use.  The moxiebox project supplies the
simulator, as well as crt0 and some custom moxie runtime libraries.
The 'moxiebox-gcc' compiler is configured to link everything in the
right order, including newlib, the custom crt0 and sandbox runtime
library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not clear how things will develop, but one thing that's come up
is extending the moxie ISA to include new instructions in support of
crypto activities.  We'll just have to see.  You can follow along at
&lt;a href="http://github.com/jgarzik/moxiebox"&gt;http://github.com/jgarzik/moxiebox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>New Site</title><link href="http://moxielogic.github.io/blog/new-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-02T00:40:00-05:00</updated><author><name>green</name></author><id>tag:moxielogic.github.io/blog,2014-12-02:new-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had finally had enough of the wiki spammers, and decided to migrate
all of my content over to a static github hosted site.  I believe all
of the blog entries migrated over now, and I'm in the process of
migrating the wiki content over to pages you can link to from the
sidebar (see
&lt;a href="http://moxielogic.org/blog/pages/architecture.html"&gt;Architecture&lt;/a&gt;,
for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I ever get around to learning how htaccess rewrite rules work, I
should be able to redirect RSS feed subscribers to the new link.  But
until then, nobody will get any new entries in their readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I get this out of the way, I'll post something new and amazing
about moxie.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>